

Julio Cesar Ramirez Paredes

Profile

Bachelor of civil engineering, expert in engineering solutions for fluid mechanics and computational fluid dynamics in challenging problems.

Interest in fluid mechanics and programming languages.

Outstanding learning capacity, motivation to continue learning and orientation to achieve results in my career.

Social Network

Mz. C1 Lt. 26

- Mario Cavagnaro Bellavista, Callao
- **J** (+51) 939196012
- **✓** julio.ramirez@pucp.edu.pe
- in Linkedin
- Github
- Pucp
- **@** Website
- Resume

Languages

English Portuguese

Programming

C++
Fortran
Python

EDUCATION

• Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú Bachelor's Degree in Civil Engineering

San Miguel ,PE Jul 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Hidro Mayu

Lambayeque, PE

Structural equipment installation assistant

Mar 2023

• Mechanics of materials and structural analysis: Training to teachers about the equipment of the Universidad Nacional Pedro Ruiz Gallo's structural engineering laboratory

• Hidro Mayu

Huacho, PE

Hydraulic equipment maintenance support

Nov 2022

- Fluid mechanics and open channel hydraulics: Maintenance and training to teachers and students about the equipment of the Universidad Nacional José Faustino Sánchez Carrión's hydraulics laboratory
- Centro de Investigación y Tecnología del Agua Barranco, PE Research Assistant Sep 2019 - Nov 2021
 - **Urban air quality**: Numerical simulation of the navier equations for incompresible newtonian flow in air fluid in urban environments using Openfoam.
 - Dam break: Numerical modeling of the shallow water equation for incompresible newtonian flow in dam break escenarios using Telemac-2D.
- Universidad de Ingeniería y Tecnologia

Barranco, PE

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2019 - Nov 2021

- Mathematics III: Solid understanding of linear algebra and numerical methods.
- Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú San Miguel, PE
 Jefe de Práctica Mar 2019 Jul 2020
 - Open Channel Hydraulics: Solid understading of channel morphology, hydraulic engineering and sediment transport.
- MJ & Asociados Water Resources Consulting Lima, PE
 Practicing civil engineer Mar 2019 Jun 2019
 - **River flood**: Observation of flood zone in the Moquegua river under extreme flood condition to investigate the resilience of the infrastructure.

Courses

Master python for data science inLearning 2021

Programming CFD OpenFOAM
 CFD Direct 2021

Fire modelling with OpenFOAM OpenFOAM 2020

OpenFOAM turbulence CFD Support 2019

OpenFOAM advanced CFD Support 2019

Open source hydraulics modelling of shalUniversidad Nacional de

low water flow

Ingeniería Hydraulics

Laboratory 2018

Autocad 2018 advanced Centro de Cómputo UNIMASTER 2018

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Programming Languages: C++, C, Fortran, Python, R, Javascript, Scilab, Matlab, CSS, HTML, Bash y Lisp.
- **Softwares**: Hecras, Telemac, Flo-2D, River2D, OpenFOAM, Qgis, Arcgis, Emacs, Pointwise, Tecplot, Blender, Autocad, Latex, Ubuntu, Git y Aws.
- Tiping: Typing speed of 65 wpm Monkeytype, Keybr.